# **Changhao Wang** | Curriculum Vitae

2103 Etcheverry Hall, Berkeley, California, 94720

☑ changhaowang@berkeley.edu • ⓒ changhaowang.github.io

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at UC Berkeley advised by Prof. Masayoshi Tomizuka. My research interest lies in the interdisciplinary combination of robotics, optimization, artificial intelligence and control theories with applications to robotic manipulation and motion planning.

## **Education Background**

## Academic Qualifications.....

University of California, Berkeley

Ph.D. Major: Controls, Mechanical Engineering Department. **GPA:4.0** 

University of California, Berkeley

Visiting Student Researcher, College of Engineering

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

B.S. Major: Mechanical Engineering, School of Mechanical Engineering

Berkeley, CA

2018.8-2023.6 (expected)

Berkeley, CA 2017.6-2017.9

Shanghai, CHN

2014.9-2018.7

## Selected Research Experiences

#### Robotic Bottle Filpping and Landing with TRPO and Adaptive MPC

**UC** Berkeley

Advisor: Prof. Pieter Abbeel and Prof. Masayoshi Tomizuka

2019.9-Present

- 1. Trained a bottle flipping robot by Trust Region Policy Optimization, which can throw the bottle and let it vertivally to the ground.
- 2. Introduced a LSTM network for bottle trajectory prediction.
- 3. Combined the framework with an adaptive MPC controller to stabilize the bottle.
- 4. Tested the framework in the Pybullet Simulator. (Check the video here: https://changhaowang.github.io)

#### Worst State Trajectory Optimization for Robotic Motion Planning

**UC** Berkeley

Advisor: Prof. Masayoshi Tomizuka

2019.4-2019.9

- 1. Proposed a novel trajectory optimization framework called worst state trajectory optimization (WSTO), which can take in-between states collision into consideration efficiently.
- 2. Introduced a state parameterization method that can represent every state on a continuous trajectory by only one parameter.
- 3. Tested the proposed algorithm in several scenarios and found the WSTO framework was able to achieve a higher success rate without sacrificing the time.

#### Robust Deformation Model Approximation for Cable Manipulation

**UC** Berkeley

Advisor: Prof. Masayoshi Tomizuka

2018.9-2019.3

- 1. Proposed a real-time robust deformation model approximation method by solving robust weighted least squares.
- 2. Combined the robsut model approximation method with SPR tracking algorithm in the presence of sensor noise outliers, and occlusions.

#### **Deformable Object Manipulation by Transfer Learning**

**UC** Berkeley

Advisor: Prof. Masayoshi Tomizuka

2017.6-2017.9

- 1. Designed a robust real-time tracker that estimates the state of a deformable object even under occlusion and among outliers.
- 2. Applied a transfer learning-based method to do robotic manipulation tasks like grasping, rope knotting, and cloth folding
- 3. Designed state recognition, trajectory warping, and failure detection algorithms with non-rigid point set registration to improve the efficiency and robustness of deformable object manipulation.

4. Proposed a tangent space non-rigid registration method to prevent objects from being overstretched.

## Vision Based Object Classification and Size Recognition

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Advisor: Prof. Ye Ding

2018.1-2018.6

- 1. Proposed a novel uniform framework for Object Classification and Size Recognition.
- 2. For object classification, SHOT descriptor was utilized, which combine the signature and histogram feature together to achieve a better performance.
- 3. For size recognition, we combined RANSAC and color-based region grow algorithms together to segment the target objects. PCA and Least Square method were used for size detection.
- 4. Spectral clustering was introduced to deal with overlapping and occlusion situations. It is showed this method can achieve the best performance among other clustering algorithms, such as K-Means and Gaussian Mixture Model

## Path Planning and Navigation of a Fuel-cell Powered UAV

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Advisor: Prof. Xinjun Sheng

2016.7-2018.5

- 1. Designed a new UAV model based on a new material (AZ31B) which can perfectly fit the Fuel-Cell UAV.
- Designed an embedded system using microcontrollers for battery management which can control and balance the output of Fuel Cells and Lithium Cells automatically so that the power of the cell can keep up with the motor's change.
- 3. Designed the path planning system, in addition to PID, using NURBS to improve the efficiency and robustness of the UAV.
- 4. Developed a system, based on an optical flow sensor and PID, to control the position and navigation of UAVs during flight.

#### Intelligent Furniture and its Control System Design

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

2015.9-2016.2

Advisor: Prof. Xingcai Lyu

- 1. Designed an automatically switched window based on a feedback system, using Arduino, a temperature transducer, and a humidity sensor, which can automatically determine the amount that a window should be open based on collected data.
- 2. Designed an automatically-folding table using UG and Solidworks and created a new 1 DOF mechanism to unfold the table.
- 3. Designed the control system of the table using Arduino Mega 2560 and programmed an App by MIT App Inventor on the phone that can identify the voice of the user and who can then control the table to unfold.

## **Awards**

o Chin Leung Shui Chun Fellowship (UC Berkeley)	2020
<ul> <li>Graduate Division Block Grant Award (UC Berkeley)</li> </ul>	2020
<ul> <li>Outstanding Graduate of Shanghai Jiao Tong University</li> </ul>	2018
<ul> <li>HONGYI Scholarship (Top 8 at SJTU)</li> </ul>	2018
Shanghai Jiao Tong University Scholarship	2015-2017
o The First Prize in Shanghai in the China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modelling	g 2016
o The Second Prize in the China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modelling (Top 1%	) 2016
o 2016 SGMW Scholarship (4/485)	2016
<ul> <li>Best Innovative Award of School of Mechanical Engineering (1/374)</li> </ul>	2015

## **Publications and Patents**

- [1] **Changhao Wang** and Masayoshi Tomizuka. Worst state trajectory optimization: A novel framework for motion planning. In *2020 Robotics Science and Systems (RSS)*, Submitted.
- [2] Te Tang\*, **Changhao Wang\***, and Masayoshi Tomizuka. A framework for manipulating deformable linear objects by coherent point drift. *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters*, 3(4):3426–3433, 2018.
- [3] Shiyu Jin\*, **Changhao Wang\***, and Masayoshi Tomizuka. Robust deformation model approximation for cable manipulation. In 2019 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2019.

- [4] **Changhao Wang**. The use of nano technology in solar cell. *IEnergy Conservation in Petroleum and Petrochemical Industry*, 5, 2016.
- [5] Changhao Wang, Yikai Hu, and Mengjie Jing. Fuel-cell uav frame based on az31b, 2017. 201710408661.1.

# **Technical and Personal skills**

- o Programming Languages: Proficient in: Matlab, Python, C++, Arduino, TeX, ROS, PCL
- o Industry Software Skills: SolidWorks, Origin, Ansys (Intermediate), Most MS Office products
- o General Business Skills: Good presentation skills, Works well in a team.